Privacy Policy | CARS                   

To donate call [855-500-RIDE (7433)](tel:855-337-4377)

Privacy Policy
==============

We are committed to respecting your privacy at Charitable Adult Rides & Services, Inc. The following Privacy Policy sets forth our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website.  
  
**By accessing or using this Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and consent to the collection and use of information as discussed in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, do not access this Website.**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Material changes will be conspicuously posted on the Website. Your continued use of our Website following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the changes.

### Contact Us

Questions regarding this Privacy Policy should be directed to Charitable Adult Rides & Services, Inc. by emailing marketingsupport@careasy.org.

### Non-US Users

Charitable Adult Rides & Services, Inc. (CARS, Inc.) is a non-profit corporation incorporated in California and tax-exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. The services available on this Website are provided by or on behalf of CARS, Inc. and its licensees based in the United States. The personal information that you provide will be transferred to and maintained in CARS, Inc. records in the United States. If you do not consent to this transfer, do not accept this privacy policy or otherwise use the Website.

CARS, Inc. does not represent that the materials and information offered on this website are appropriate or available for use in locations outside the U.S. If you access the site from outside the U.S., you do so on your own initiative and at your own risk, and you are solely responsible for complying with any applicable laws from the jurisdiction in which you are located.

### Information We Collect

**Personally Identifiable Information**

"Personally identifiable information" is any information that can be used to identify, contact, or locate you, such as your full name, mailing address, telephone number, email address, and password(s). CARS, Inc. may request your personally identifiable information at various times when you use the Website, such as when you email us at one of the addresses on our "Contact Us" page, otherwise sign up for services from CARS, Inc., or make a donation via the Website. You may also provide information to CARS, Inc. and/or its vendors or partners by contacting CARS, Inc. or members of CARS, Inc. via phone for the purposes of a donation or otherwise. We may collect your full name, mailing address, phone number and e-mail address. If you place a donation, we may also be required to collect your Tax Identification Number for tax purposes. CARS, Inc. will keep a copy of your Tax Identification Number only until donation services and requirements are complete. This information is not maintained or stored on an on-going basis. CARS, Inc. also collects certain information via this Website that is not personally identifiable as described below. By choosing to provide us with your personally identifiable information you are consenting to the required transfer and processing of such information.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

"Non-personally identifiable information" refers to information that does not identify a specific individual. Some examples of non-personally identifiable information include the Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") of the website you visited before ours, the one to which you go next, which Internet browser you are using, cookies used to uniquely identify your browser, and your Internet Protocol address, which is a number automatically assigned to your computer that allows Internet servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order to communicate online. We collect and use non-personally identifiable information in the following ways.

**Analytics**

Like many websites, we use a third party service provider, such as Google Analytics, to collect information about your use of our Website. We track data about traffic to our Website and your visit to and experience of our Website, which serves as information we use to improve our Website structure and content.

We may pair your IP address with information about how you use our site, and we may associate your IP address with PII you provide. Our systems do not recognize browser "Do Not Track" signals. California residents are entitled once a year to request and obtain certain information regarding any disclosure of PII we make to third parties for direct marketing purposes during the prior calendar year. While CARS, Inc. does not typically make such disclosures to third parties, we comply with the law by allowing users to ask us not to disclose their PII to third parties for marketing purposes. To opt out, consistently exercise your opt-out choice when prompted to do so by the website or send an email to marketingsupport@careasy.org including the CARS, Inc. website as the subject line along with your full name, email address, and postal address.

As noted above, we allow analytics vendors and other third parties to collect non-personally identifiable information and other data about users who visit our site. We cannot always control third party cookies stored on your device from visiting our site, but you may visit the relevant third party's website directly to manage these cookies.

**Cookies**

CARS, Inc. may use cookies to track the use of our Website or Iframes and to facilitate and enhance your experience on our Website. "Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies enable us to facilitate access to different aspects of our Website. For example, by showing when and how you and others visit our Website, cookies help us to see which pages of the Website are popular and which are not. Cookies can also help us to improve your enjoyment of this Website, for example, by remembering your address or other personal information when you request information or services on the Website.

We use session cookies during the time of your visit on the Website that expire when you exit and we also use more permanent cookies that are two year tracking cookies so we can recognize you if you return to the Website. For users who log into the CARS, Inc. website, we store the following cookies: (1) an authentication cookie after a valid username and password are entered; (2) a cookie storing a link to the user's home page on the CARS, Inc. site; and (3) cookies logging the month and year currently selected on the user's calendar control.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can disable this function so that your browser will not accept cookies. Please be aware that disabling this function may limit your use and enjoyment of this Website.

**Aggregated Information**

In addition, we may take personally identifiable information you provide to us and aggregate it with information of other users and customers such that the data no longer identifies you. We may use and share aggregated information that does not uniquely identify you when it enables us to improve and enrich our services and Website content.

**IP Addresses**

CARS, Inc. logs IP addresses for systems administration purposes and to track geographic analytics to help us determine where our Website users are located. IP addresses are not used to track a user's session. This information only helps us determine how often different areas of our site are visited. We do not link IP address to any information that is personally identifiable.

Like most other Websites, CARS, Inc. servers automatically track certain information about your activity on our Website. This information allows us to keep our Website running efficiently. This information includes: the browser you are using (such at Netscape, Internet Explorer, etc.); your operating system (such as Macintosh, Windows XP, etc.); your IP address; and the referring URL and all CARS, Inc. URLs you visit.

**Other Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

We may also use web beacons and pixel tags. Web beacons (also called single pixel gifs or web bugs) are Internet tools, such as transparent images on the website or in e-mails that we may send you that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or an e-mail opened. For example, when you ask us to send you information, we may use web beacons to determine how many of the e-mails we sent were actually opened. A pixel tag is a type of web beacon embedded in an image on the website. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including a banner ad, may contain a pixel tag.

### Data Use, Sharing and Your Choices

We may use the personally identifiable information that you provide to allow us to send you the information and materials you require or otherwise contact you as you request.

You may also opt-in-to receiving additional marketing communications from CARS, Inc. and its authorized partners for marketing and other purposes communicated to you. If you choose to opt-in-to such communications, we will use your personally identifiable information for the purpose indicated and we will share your information with one or more CARS, Inc. authorized partners. If you choose to opt-out of any such communications, you may do so at any time and without penalty by clicking on the link provided in the email to unsubscribe or by contacting us at the number provided. We will also use your information to process any donation you may place or otherwise provide you about information regarding your donation. You may not unsubscribe to communications regarding your donation. Unsubscribing to marketing communications from CARS, Inc. will remove you from our marketing database, but we will still need to communicate with you about your donation or other request. As CARS, Inc. works on behalf of the partner in whom you donate, it is likely that your PII will be shared with said partner to process your request or to make aware of a donation. For instance, if you were to donate on behalf of a given charity, your PII, provided to CARS, Inc., may be shared with said charity to make them aware of your gift.

In addition to sharing your information with authorized partners, we may share your information with our affiliates, licensees, vendors, service providers and agents who assist us in providing our services and processing your donation, such as our call center and vendors that provide towing or auction services. Our vendors, service providers and agents are required by contract to keep your information confidential and they are not permitted to use your information for any purpose other than providing services to CARS, Inc. CARS, Inc. works with a partner call center and number of auction houses and tow companies, nationwide, to process your donation. For further information regarding our service providers and agents, please contact us with your request as set forth above in Contact us.

Finally, we will share your information if required by law to do so; when required to protect and defend the rights or property of CARS, Inc.; to investigate reports of fraud or of misuse or unauthorized use of the Website; when CARS, Inc. believes it appropriate to protect its users, employees, or the public in an emergency situation; and when required to enforce or defend the conditions of any agreement with CARS, Inc. CARS, Inc. does not sell, rent, loan, or otherwise provide the contact information or other PII of any donor to third parties for any purpose other than those set forth herein.

In the event that CARS, Inc. or its business assets are bought, sold, or otherwise transferred or reorganized, the transferred business assets will likely include the information that has been collected and will be transferred to the new owner, who will continue to be bound by this Privacy Policy.

### Links from This Website

This policy only addresses CARS, Inc.'s collection and use of your information from this Website, except as otherwise provided. If you disclose your information to others in connection with your use of our Website, or any other Website (including sites linked to our Website(, you are subject to the privacy policies that they apply. CARS, Inc. does not have control over the privacy policies applied by any other party that you may disclose information to when linking to or from our Website. If you would like information on any other party's privacy policy, you should contact that party directly, and we encourage you to do so.

### Security

CARS, Inc. employs reasonable security measures to help protect the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, including the use of firewalls, intrusion prevention systems, and SSL encryption. We use encryption technology such as Secure Sockets Layering (SSL) to encrypt information, including Tax Identification Numbers or other customer information, before it is transmitted. We limit the information we provide to outside companies with whom we contract only to what they need to carry out their responsibilities.

Please understand that despite these efforts, we cannot guarantee the security of your information given the current state of the Internet. We cannot guarantee that your information will always be protected from interception, misappropriation, misuse or alteration. We cannot guarantee that your information will not be disclosed or accessed by accidental circumstances, such as a hardware or software failure, or the unauthorized acts of third parties. You provide all information to CARS, Inc. at your own risk.

### Access by Children

CARS, Inc. recognizes the importance of safeguarding children's privacy, so our website supports and complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA") and other applicable laws. Our Website is not intended for children and we will not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. Contributors using our Services and recipients receiving contributions must be of legal age to form a contract. Generally, the legal age to form a contract begins at age 18. Please do not attempt to use the Website or to send any personally identified information to us if you are under the age of 18.

We encourage parents to talk to their children about their use of the Internet and the information they disclose online. If you discover your child has provided us with personally identifiable information, you may contact us, as described in the first paragraph of this policy, to ask that we delete this information from our records. We will use reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from our databases upon receiving your request. If we learn that we have inadvertently gathered personally identifiable information from a child under the age of 13, we will erase it promptly.

### Updating Your Information

If you wish to update, correct or otherwise have access to your personally identifiable information in our records, please contact us with your request as set forth above in Contact Us.

##### California Office

###### 4669 Murphy Canyon Road, Ste. 200

###### San Diego, CA 92123

##### [Phone: 855-500-RIDE (7433)](tel:855-500-7433)

##### EIN: 27-4327126

###### All donations will be a charitable benefit to one of thousands of our nonprofit partners and CARS (Charitable Adult Rides & Services), a 501 (c)(3) nonprofit that provides transportation solutions for seniors.

© . All rights reserved.
